Hey, Kobato-chan! Kobato-chan!
Yes?
Read this!
Huh?
The Firefly’s Light…
Read it.
Huh?
Can't you read, Kobato-chan?
I can read!
When nighttime came, the
riverbank became pitch black.
Tonight, it seems like the moon is taking a break.
I can’t see anything!
I saw it!
Eh!
Kobato-chan, you skipped something again.
Eh?
S-Sorry. Um…
You’re as slow as ever, I see.
Just keep trying, Kobato-chan.
Yes!
You’re still messing up?
Hello. This is Yomogi Preschool.
I thought I told you that that’s unacceptable.
The preschool is open right now, so if you’ll please excuse me.
Kobato-chan, you fell down again.
Yeah, you did!
Dobato! What are you doing at a serious time like this?!
Kobato-chan, bye-bye.
Bye-bye!
Kobato-chan, Kobato-chan!
What is it, Marina-chan?
It would be nice if you could get
better at reading picture books, right?
Yes! I’ll do my best.
It’s okay. You’ll get better someday.
Yes!
Um…
I want the kids to enjoy my storytelling, so I’d like to practice reading more.
Is it all right if I borrow this?
S-Sure. I don’t mind.
I’m going to try my best so I can read better!
Keep trying.
Yes!
The firefly lived all alone for a long time.
So long that he forgot there
were other fireflies out there.
Being all alone is lonely, isn’t it?
Maybe.
On this completely dark day, he felt like
something wonderful was going to happen.
Hey!
Huh?
Can I help you with something?
Yeah.
Could you stop?
Eh?
I said, stop reading that!
Um, why is that?
That guy sure puts out some bad vibes.
Huh?
What?
The old man from before.
You’re right.
What’s this?
Doesn’t he look completely different than before?
I wonder if something’s bothering him.
I’m sorry!
Do you not have a house?
How’d you come up with that?
The truth is that, until just a little while ago I was living in the park,
but thanks to Sayaka-sensei and Chitose-san,
I have a soft and fluffy futon to sleep on now.
Futons really are the best.
Huh?
If you like, would you care to come to my home?
I don’t need assistance from someone I don’t know.
I’m Hanato Kobato and this is Ioryogi-san.
Don’t associate with me.
Um…
I wonder why he’s so upset?
The firefly saw a small but beautiful light off in the distance.
I wonder how I can get closer to that?
I really am slow.
Tomorrow, I’m going to continue to do my best!
I overslept again!
Just how flaky can you be?
If you show up late again,
Fujimoto won’t be nice about it.
Fast!
What?
What is it, miss?
Good morning.
Do you have some kind of business here?
We came to collect the debt!
What? Debt?
These guys seem dangerous.
Come on! Eat it!
Kids really love these.
Come on!
Please stop!
What are you doing?
You bumped into me and
didn’t even say you were sorry.
What are you doing? Let go!
Keep your hands off the kids!
Fujimoto-san!
You little…
That hurts!
Mess with us, will you?
Please stop!
Sayaka-sensei!
I’ve asked you before to please not come while the preschool is open!
You’re giving us orders?
But aren’t you the one who’s
not returning our money, Sensei?
You shouldn’t be taking this lightly.
Just because our boss is nice to you…
We can have this conversation after the preschool closes.
So please-
If you give us what we’re asking for, we’ll be gone in a jiffy. So…
Give us what we want!
You-!
She…
P-Please go home.
K-Kobato-chan.
Please go home!
We don’t have the time to play with brats like you.
Please go home.
What’s up with this woman?
Mr. Police Officer!
Please help us! There are scary people here!
Please hurry!
We’ll leave for now, but we’ll keep coming back unless you give us the money!
Let go!
Sayaka-sensei, are you all right?
Yeah, I’m fine.
Toshihiko-kun?
Are you all right?
They’re fake tears, so I’m okay.
I thought they'd leave if I called for a police officer.
Is that right? Well, they really did leave.
Amazing!
Toshihiko-kun, you’re awesome!
Not really.
If they come again, I’ll run them off!
Dobato, you did good today.
But how long can I continue like this?
The phone call yesterday must have been from them.
Sayaka-sensei is in trouble.
I wonder if there's anything I can do to help her.
But you have no money.
But if I can help her pay the debt, I could heal Sayaka-sensei’s heart.
What is it?
Are you an idiot?!
It’s him.
He’s still there. What’s he doing?
This is…
Could it be…!
Excuse me!
Are you not feeling well?
I’m fine. Nothing’s wrong.
Um…
Isn’t there anything I can do for you?
If something’s bothering you…
Nothing’s bothering me. I have a house.
I just like being here.
Is that so?
The picture book from yesterday…
I borrowed it from the preschool.
I’ve been practicing, but somehow I’m not getting any better.
I thought I told you not to read it.
Why’s that?
Everyone really likes this story.
That’s why I want to read this well…
Please, I’m asking you not to read it!
Eh?
It’s nothing.
Just forget it.
Does he really hate this book that much?
What are you doing here, Fujimoto-san?
I live here.
You’re my neighbor?
Well, isn’t it obvious?
Um…
What is it?
A man I met in the park told me not to read this book.
Did you meet Mori-san?
Mori-san?
Is there something wrong with Ioryogi-san?
No, he’s the book’s author.
What! Really?!
He’s famous in this area.
But why did he tell me not to read the book, then?
Who knows.
But…
They say that it’s the very last book he wrote.
The last book?
A firefly lived alongside a beautiful stream.
This firefly lived all alone for a very long time.
So long that he eventually forgot there were other fireflies.
One dark night, when there was no moon,
the firefly saw a small but
beautiful light off in the distance.
“What is it?” he thought as he approached it.
It was a female insect.
“So beautiful! What kind of insect are you?” he asked.
“I’m the same as you, a firefly,” answered the female firefly.
The female firefly continued,
“Why is it that you don’t sparkle?”
The firefly that was always alone had forgotten how to sparkle.
So, the female firefly explained to the lonely firefly how to sparkle.
And with that, the two fireflies stayed together on the bank of the stream,
and grew much closer, while sparkling together.
Maybe that old man has forgotten how to sparkle as well.
I don’t know why, but he does
seem like the firefly in that book.
I wonder if there is something I can do for him.
Hey! Hey! What are you starting?
I’m going to find it!
Huh?
Hey!
Are you free this evening?
Let’s go watch the fireflies!
I’ll be waiting by the stream at Hachimanyama.
The firefly remembered.
I am a firefly.
I can shine like you.
You’re getting better at this, aren’t you?
I’m sure he can remember how to sparkle.
But it seems like he’s not coming.
You came!
Yeah, there was no way around it.
Um, the fireflies haven’t come out yet.
Why’d you say something like that?
“Let’s go see the fireflies.”
“I’ll be waiting by the stream at Hachimanyama.”
You sound just like Naoko.
Naoko-san?
She was… my beloved.
The pictures…
Naoko drew those pictures.
She said a firefly story would be
good, so I went ahead and wrote it.
After that, she drew the pictures.
Let’s go see the fireflies!
Come on, I said let’s go see them.
You promised, didn’t you?
Yes, I understand.
I don’t have the time.
Don’t say things like that.
I found a place no one knows about.
I said I don’t have time.
I’ll be waiting by the stream at Hachimanyama.
Hello? Yes. Yes.
In the end, I didn’t go.
Back then, I was very busy.
I had a lot of deadlines approaching.
Then your beloved went all alone.
It was beautiful.
She said she wanted to show it to me too.
There was something sad about the pictures she drew, but they were beautiful.
So I wrote a new story that was sad, yet beautiful.
A while after the book was finished…
Finally, you have a break?
Yeah, I’m waiting in the same park as always.
Naoko! Hey, Naoko! Hang on!
Soutarou-san?
Yeah, it’s me.
Is there anything you want?
I’ll bring you anything.
Fireflies.
Fireflies… I wanted to see them with you.
Why didn’t I go with her back then?
All she wanted was to see them with me.
Why didn’t I…
I’m leaving.
Please wait!
Just a little…
If you wait just a little longer, surely…
Are you all right?
I-I’m sorry!
This place…
Naoko stood here, drawing.
Here.
Fireflies.
Huh? You haven’t seen fireflies before?
What? Sorry, okay?
Then, let’s go together.
If you don’t see the real thing, then…
But there aren’t any fireflies in this area.
I’ll definitely show them to you.
It’s a promise.
A promise, huh…
Pretty, aren’t they?
The fireflies.
They really are beautiful.
Yeah.
The old man remembered how to sparkle.
He’s writing again.
As proof…
…look at this.
There’s one more!
Which means…
You healed him.
I was able to help Mori-san.
This time it’s a perfect 100 points… or so I’d like to say.
But at the library, you treated me poorly.
Kobato, 80 points.
Oh, thank you so much!
From now on, we have to go at a much faster pace.
Yes! I’ll do my best!
But I must be getting soft, giving you 80 points after that. Maybe 50 would be better…
No! 80 points is good.
Then, I guess it’s…
Yes?
79 points.
That’s so unfair!